A Finding Aid to the National Society of Mural Painters Records, 1895 - circa 2007, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Financial and Legal Records, 1895-1996; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 8-10
  This series consists primarily of the treasurers' files containing correspondence regarding the payment of dues and financial reports. Other materials found here include ledgers and cash books, the majority of which are organized by member and note the payment date of dues received. Banking records consist of permission forms noting which officers are allowed access to the society's bank accounts. Legal records include a draft of an agreement and records relating to changing the name of the society in 1937.
  - Treasurer Files, 1895-1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
  - Treasurer Files, 1917-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1-11)
  - Ledgers, Cash Books, 1895-1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12-20)
  - Banking Material, Permissions, 1934-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
  - Tax Preparation and Exemption Records, 1944-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3-5)
  - Agreement, Draft, circa 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Name Change Records, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Entrance Fee Receipts, 1940; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, Bills, and Invoices, 1938-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 9-17)
- Printed Material, 1915-2000; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 10-11
  Exhibition catalogs and annoucements, informational brochures and pamphlets, newsletters, and a portfolio of members' works were published by National Society of Mural Painters. Clippings concern the society's members and its activities.
  - Admission Tickets and Printing Plate, 1923; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 18-19)
  - Clippings, 1934-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 20-23)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, 1915-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 24-27)
  - Informational Brochures and Pamphlets, 1915-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 28-34)
  - Newsletters, 1936-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 35-41)
  - Portfolio, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Portfolio, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
  - Reproductions of Works of Art, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Scrapbook, 1923-1935; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.2 Linear feet Box 11
  One mixed media scrapbook contains correspondence, clippings, invitations, exhibition announcements, and some reproductions of works of art.
  - Scrapbook 1, 1923-1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Photographic Material, circa 1900-1997; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 12-18
  Photographic materials consists of scattered photographs, transparencies, lantern slides, and photo collages of members, artwork, members with their artwork, meetings, exhibitions, and events. The photo collages typically include a photo of the artist and examples of their work. Also found are lantern slides, mostly of works of art, and of Francis D. Millett in his studio and with his murals and of J. Scott Williams with his art. A list of the lantern slides is found within the records, but it is unclear whether the list corresponds to all or some of the lantern slides.
  - Exhibitions and Events, 1970s-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
  - Meetings, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Works of Art, 1970s-1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - Transparencies, circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - List of Lantern Slides, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1900-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1900-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1900-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1-6)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1900-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1-6)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1900-circa 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  - Oversized Photo Collages, circa 1995; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)